Guide to the Matthew F. McHugh papers, 1974-1992.
McHugh, Matthew F papers
- Correspondence by Topic (Box 64)
  Department of Justice, Department of Labor, Internal Revenue Service (2), Jewish Discrimination, Interns (10), Human Rights Violations in Foreign Countries, Department of the Interior, Interior & Insular Affairs, Health Care, Department of Health, Education, & Welfare, House Reform, Department of Housing and Urban Development.
- Correspondence by Topic (Box 229)
  D of Agriculture, Delaware - Fleischmanns, Delaware - M*Ark, Delaware - MIP, Delaware - Miscellaneous, Delaware - Ours Associates, Delaware - Roxbury-Grand Gorge Water System, Delaware - Stamford HUD, Delaware - SUNY Agriculture & Technology, Delaware - Walton Flooding, Delaware - Walton Village Flooding, D of Energy, NYS D of Environmental Conservation, DMSO (Dimethylsulfoxide), Energy (2 files), Energy - Houses East, Energy - Home Heating Oil, Energy - Gasoline, Energy - Background Memos, Environmental Protection Agency, Farmer’s Home Administration (2 files), US Fire Administration, D of Health Education & Welfare, D of Housing & Urban Development, Upper Delaware Park Project 1980, Multi-County - Hospitals, Multi-County - East District Hospitals, Multi-County - Health Planning, Multi-County - Hospital Medicare Administration & Cost Containment, Interior & Insular - Wild & Scenic, Interior & Insular - Correspondence, Interior & Insular - Clippings, Interior & Insular - 1979.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-01, 1975 - 1976 (Box 189)
  Action, D of Agriculture - General (2 files), Agriculture Committee, Sub-Committee of Department Operations, Investment, and Oversight, Sub-Committee Dairy & Poultry, Abortion PRO, Abortion CON, Agriculture - World Food Problem, D of Agriculture - Broome County, D of Agriculture - Chemung County, D of Agriculture - Delaware County, D of Agriculture - Sullivan County, D of Agriculture - Tioga County, D of Agriculture - Tompkins County, D of Agriculture - Ulster County, Congratulations from MFM 1975, Congratulations from MFM 1976, Congratulations to MFH 1976, Canning Lids (anti-trust), D of Commerce, Commission on Administrative Review, Condolences, D of Agriculture - Food & Nutrition Services, D of Agriculture - Food Stamps, American Indians, AT&T, Auto Comnpanies & Dealers, Bicentennial, Agriculture Committee, Sub-Committee on Domestic Marketing & Consumer Relations, D of Agriculture Animal & Plant Inspection Services, D of Agriculture FmHA, Agriculture Committee, Dairy Sub-Committee, Hearings in Binghamton, Cornell, Farm Organizations, Consumers, Thanks to Witnesses, Dear Colleague Letters, Requests to Testify, Press Releases, Miscellaneous Materials, State Officials, Unable to Attend, Witnesses, Thanks for Comments.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-02, 1975 - 1976 (Box 190)
  Agriculture - Food Stamps, Agriculture - General, Agriculture - Naitonal Research Policy Act, Agriculture - Timber Management, Appropriations - general, Appropriations - Defense Sub Comp, Armed Services - general, Banking, Currency, & Housing, Banking Currency NYC Fiscal Crisis, Budget Committee, District of Columbia, Education, Education & Labor - Labor, Education & Labor - HR 5900, Education & Labor - Common Situs Picketing PRO, Education & Labor - Common Situs Picketing CON.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-04, 1975 - 1976 (Box 106)
  Congressional Rural Caucus (4 files) 1975, Consumer Product Safety Division, 1974 Correspondence, Cost Accounting Standards Board, Council on Wage & Price Stability, Court Reform, Crume, Death Penalty, Defense, Democratic Congressional Caucus, Democratic Congressional Caucus 1974, Democratic Convention 1976, Democratic Convention Platform Committee Task Force (2 files), Draft, Drugs - Marijuana, Economy, Education, Education - NYS Legislation, Education - School Lunch Program, Employment with McHugh, Employment with Government, Energy 1976, Energy - Nuclear Plants, Energy - Nuclear, Energy - Natural Gas, Energy - Oil, Energy - General Jul-Dec 1975, Energy - General Jan-Jun 1975, Energy - Gas & Electric utilities, Energy Research and Development Administration.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-05, 1975 - 1976 (Box 186)
  Education & Labor - General, Education & Labor - Child & Family Service Act, Education & Labor - School Lunch, Education & Labor - Labor - Green Thumb, Education & Labor - OSHA, Government Operations - General, House Administration, Interior & Insular Affairs, International Affairs, Interstate and Foreign Commerce -, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Health Sub-Committee, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Malpractice, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Truck Weights, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Vitamins, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - HR 1087.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-06, 1975 - 1976 (Box 183)
  Environment - Auto Emissions, Environment - General, Environment - EPA, Federal Aeronautics Administration, Federal Communications Commission, Federal Election Commission, Federal Energy Administration, Ford Administration, Filing System, Food & Drug Administration, Federal Trade Commission, Foreign Affairs - Chile, Foreign Affairs - Indo-China, Foreign Policy - General, Foreign Affairs - Soviet Union, Foreign Affairs - United Nations, Foreign Affairs - Vietnam A-L, Foreign Affairs - Vietnam M-Z, Freshman Class, Gas Rationing, Gay Lib, General Services Administration, GIOIA Grace, Government Spending - General, Government Spending - National Debt, Gun Control 1975-1976 (14 files).
- Correspondence by Topic 094-07, 1975 - 1976 (Box 188)
  Health, Health - National Health Insurance, D of Health, Education, & Welfare, Hospital Association of NY, House Reform, D of Housing & Urban Development, Inflation, Insurance, Insurance - no fault, Intelligence Agencies - General, Intelligence Agencies - CIA General, Intelligence Agencies - CIA - JFK, D of Interior, Internal Revenue Service, International Trade Commission, Interns - rejected, Interns - Fall 1976, Interstate Commerce Commission, D of Justice, Labor Unions - General, D of Labor, Landsat, Machinists Association, Mayaguez Affair, Merchant Marine/Fisheries, Metric Conversion, Miscellaneous 1976 (2 files), Mutli-issue Letters, NASA, National Commission on Egg Nutrition, National Endowment for the Arts, National Institutes of Health, Sept 1975 Newsletter Responses, May 1976 Newsletter Responses, July 1976 Newsletter Responses, Northeast/Midwest Advancement Coalition, Coalition of Northeast Governors.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-08, 1975 - 1976 (Box 196)
  NYC Fiscal Crisis 1975 (16 files), NYC Other 1975-1976 (3 files), NYS Budget 1973-1976, NYS Communicatons and Utilities 1975, NYS Delegation 1975-1976, NYS Delegation AD Hoc Welfare SubCommittee, NYS D of Education, NYS Federal Legislation, NYS D of Health, NYS D of Labor, NYS State Legislature, NYS Politics, NYS NYPIRG (Public Interest Research Group), NYS Utilities, Nixon, Nurses Association, Olympics, Optometric Association, Organizations, Organizations - Farm Bureau & Grange, Parochial Schools, Pensions, Political Prisoners, Postal Service, Press Releases, 1976 Questionnaire, Railroads, US Railway Association.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-09, 1975 - 1976 (Box 197)
  Referrals, Regulatory Agencies, Religion, Requests - General (4 files, 1976), Requests - Agricultural Bulletins, Requests - Campaign Mail, Requests - Flags 1976, Requests - Flags 1975, Requests - McHugh Material, Requests - General 1975 (twelve files, by month), Requests - Legislative Materials, Requests - Publications, Revenue Sharing, Right to Privacy, ROCKEFELLER Nelson, Rules of the House, Rome Air Development Center, Small Business Administration | Milton Doktor, Senate Confirmations, SCHMITT John E., Senior Citizens, SMITH Bill (NYS Legislature), Social Security Administration, Social Security, D of State.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-10, 1975 - 1976 (Box 192)
  Select Committee on Intelligence, Select Committee on Outer Continental Shelf, Committee on Small Business, Standards of Official Conduct, Standards of Official Conduct - Wayne Hayes, Standards of Official Conduct - Sikes Investigation, Veteran’s Affairs, Ways & Means - Energy HR 6860, Ways & Means - Gas Rationing, Ways & Means - NYS Gas Tax, Ways & Means - National Health Insurance, Ways & Means - Oil Import Tariff, Ways & Means - SSI Public Assistance, Ways & Means - Social Security, Ways & Means - Taxes, Ways & Means - Special Task Force Tax Deduction HR 1659, Ways & Means - Tax Reduction Act HR 2166, Ways & Means - Unemployment Assistance.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-11, 1975 - 1976 (Box 187)
  Vietnamese Orphans, Visitor Requests, Visitors to DC (9 files), Wage & Price Controls, Ways & Means, WEISER George, Welfare, White House Tours, Women’s Rights Issues.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-12, 1975 - 1976 (Box 223)
  Taxes - General, Thank Yous from MFM (10 files) 1975 - Apr 1976, Thank Yous to MFM 1975, Thank Yous to MFM 1976, Thank Yous re Town Meetings, D of Transportation, D of Treasury, Unanswered Mail Child & Family Services Act, Unanswered Mail 1975, Unanswered Mail 1976, Unemployment, Unions (Wang paragraphs), Veterans, Veteran’s Administration, Veteran’s Administration Committee - General.
- Correspondence by Topic 094-13, 1975 - 1976 (Box 198)
  Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, Joint Committee on Printing, Judiciary, Judiciary - Cable Copyright (2 files), Judiciary - Copyright Revision (HR 2223), Judiciary - Criminal Justice Reform Act, Judiciary - Gun Control - Con, Judiciary - Gun Control - Pro, Judiciary - Illegal Aliens, Judiciary - Internal Security, Judiciary - Whitehurst Discharge Petition, Merchant Marine & Fisheries, Post Office & Civil Service, Post Office HR 55 & HR 56 (2 files), Post Office House Joint Resolution, Public Works HR 2175 & HR 5247, Public Works HR 3787 & HR 4072, Public Works & Transportation, Rules - General, Science & Technology.
- Correspondence by Topic 095, 1977 - 1978 (Box 225)
  Rules, International Relations Committee Mid-East Arms Proposal, Appropriations - Agriculture & Related Agencies, Environmental Protection Agency, International Relations, Ways & Means, Ways & Means - Taxes, Abortion, Campaign Financing Bill (3 files), Public Financing Legislation, Voluntary Job Preservation & Community Stabilization Act (2 BIG files), Meeting with Professor William White.
- Correspondence by Topic 095, 1977 - 1979 (Box 220)
  Ad Hoc Energy, Agriculture 1977 - 1979, Armed Services, Assassinations, Banking, Finance, & Urban Affairs, Budget, Education & Labor, Education & Labor - Labor, Government Operations, House Administration, Interior & Insular (2 files), Interior & Insular - Nuclear, International Relations, Interstate & Foreign Commerce - General, Interstate & Foreign Commerce - Bottle Bill, Interstate & Foreign Commerce - Health Sub-Committee, Interstate & Foreign Commerce - Communications, Interstate & Foreign Commerce - Animal, Judiciary, Merchant Marine & Fisheries, Post Office & Civil Service, Public Works & Transportation, Select Committee on Outer Continental Shelf, Science & Technology, Small Business, Veteran’s Affairs, Ways & Means - Welfare & Social Security, Ways & Means - Tax Tuition (2 files), Ways & Means - Health, Ways & Means - Health Medicare, Ways & Means - Sick Pay & Disability, Ways & Means - Public Assistance Title XX & SSI, Ways & Means - Correspondence Jan 77 - Mar 78, Ways & Means - Correspondence Apr 78 - Dec 78, Ways & Means - General.
- Correspondence by Topic 095, circa 1977 (Box 100)
  HUD Federal Disaster Assistance, Wage & Price Issues, Department of Transportation, Appalachian Regional Commission, Agriculture, USDA, FmHA, Army Corps of Engineers, Commerce Department, Civil Service Commission, Community Services Administraton, Department of Defense, Environmental Protection Agency, Federal Energy Administration, Energy Research and Development Administration, Health, Education & Welfare - Education, General Services Administration, Department of Justice, Department of Health, Education & Welfare, Department of Housing & Urban Development, Department of Interior, Department of Labor, National Endowment for the Humanities 1978, NASA, USPS, Department of Treasury - Revenue Sharing, Small Business Administration, Miscellaneous Information on Foundations, Department of State - Urban Policy, Public Works, Public Works - Round 2 - Information, Public Works - Round 2 - Tompkins, Public Works - Round 2 - Sullivan, Public Works - Round 2 - Delaware, Public Works - Round 2 - Broome, Health, Education, & Welfare Awards, National Science Foundation Awards, NYS Government - Agriculture, NYS Government - Department of Environmental Conservation, NYS Government - Education, NYS Government - Justice, NYS - New York City, NYS Government - Social Services, NYS Government - Department of State, NYS Government - Transportation, NYS Government - Miscellaneous.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-01, 1975 - 1976, 1977 - 1978 (Box 181)
  94th Congress, Recommendations 1976 (pro), McHugh voting Record, 95th Congress, Academy - Miscellaneous, Agencies - Miscellaneous, Agriculture - General, Agriculture - Utica Dairy Meeting Feb 1976, Agriculture - Dairy, Agriculture - World Food Problem, Agriculture - Veal Standards, D of Agriculture - general, D of Agriculture - Animal & Plant Inspection Service, D of Agricullure - Congressional District, D of Agriculture - Food & Nutrition Services, D of Agriculture - Food Stamps, Alcohol, Amnesty, America the Beautiful Fund, Apple Growers, Apple Day Conference 1978, Appropriations Committee, D o Army, Assassinations, Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-01, 1977 - 1978 (Box 199)
  Ad Hoc Energy, Agriculture, Armed Services, Agriculture - Food Stamps, Agriculture - Summer Feeding, Assassinations, Banking, Finance, & Urban Affairs, Budget, Commission on Administration Review, District of Columbia, Education & Labor - Education, Education & Labor - General, Education & Labor - Labor Law CON, Education & Labor - Labor Law PRO, Education & Labor - OSHA, Education & Labor - Labor - Minimum Wage, Education & Labor - Common Situs Picketing, Education & Labor - Labor, Government Operations, House Administration.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-02, 1977 - 1978 (Box 109)
  Bergland NYS Visit (Secy of Agriculture), Broome County, Busing, CAREY, Hugh, Chamber of Congress, Chemung County, Civil Aeronautics Board, Colleagues, to/from, Colleges in District, Department ofr Commerce, Committee Assignments, Community Services Agency, Complaints to MFM, Condolences from MFM, Congratulations to MFM, Congratulations from MFM, Congress, District - General, Congressional Directory, Congressional Pages, Congressional Pay Riases, Congressional Record Inserts, Congressional Record, Congressional Rural Caucus, Congressional Swearing In, Consultants Specialists, Consumer - General, Cooperatives, Cornell, Cornell Legislative Study Project, Council on Wage and Price Stability, CU Dairy Forage Project.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-02, 1977 - 1978 (Box 201)
  Interior & Insular Affairs -, Interior & Insular Affairs - Strip Mining, Interior & Insular Affairs - Nuclear, Interior & Insular Affairs - Alaska Lands, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Communications, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Bottle Bill, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - General, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Health Subcommittee, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Clean Air Act, Interstate and Foreign Commerce - Animal Bills, Judiciary, Merchant Marine & Fisheries, Post Office & Civil Service (2 files), Printing, Public Works & Transportation, Science & Technology, Standards & Official Conduct (Ethics), Veteran’s Affairs - General, Veteran’s Affairs - Compensation Benefits, Veteran’s Affairs - Pension Benefits, Veteran’s Affairs - Education Benefits (extending Delimit Date).
- Correspondence by Topic 095-03, 1976 - 1978 (Box 103)
  Department of Defense, Delaware River Basin Commission, Democratic Caucus 95th Congress, Democratic Caucus re: Robert Sikes, Democratic Caucus: Task Force on House Accounts, Democratic Caucus 96th Congress, DNC, DNCC, Democratic Steering Committee, Democratic Study Group, Democratic Study Group Executive Committee, Drugs, Economic Development Conference Elmira May 1978, Economy, Education, Employment with Government, Employment with McHugh, Endorsements, Energy (2 big files), Energy Department, Environment, EPA, Environmental Study Conference, ERA.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-04, 1975 - 1978 (Box 116)
  Fair Employment Practices Committee, FmHA, FAA, FCC, Federal Election scommission, Federal Procurement Conference, Federal Register, FERRIS, Leonard E. or Scott, FDA (2 files), Foreign Affairs (General), Foreign Affairs - Human Rights, Foreign Affairs - Israel, Foreign Affairs - South Korea, Forum on Regulation, Franking Privilege, Government Spending, GRACE, Ed, GRADY, John, Skip Hausaman Project (2 files), Gun Control.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-06, 1976 - 1978 (Box 123)
  Labor Unions, LANNING, Grace, Letters to Editors, Libraries in District, Library of Congress, MASON, Edwyn E. (NYS Senator), Members of Congress, Miscellaneous 1977-1978 (5 files), MOON, Sun Myung, MOREEN, Al, MOYNIHAN, Daniel Patrick (US Senator), National Education Association, New Member Caucus, New York City, New York State, NYS Delegation Ad Hoc Dairy Committee, NYS Democratic Congressional Delegation, NYS Legislature, Newsletters, No Greater Love, Northeastern Coalition, NOVAK, Joseph, Nursing Homes, Office Procedures, Office of Management and Budget, Organizations, Phone Hour Alphabetical File 1976, Phone Hour Alphabetical File 1977, Phone Hour Alphabetical File 1978.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-07, 1977 - 1978 (Box 130)
  Postal Service, Private Bills, Press Requests, Questionnaire, Questionnaires to MFM, Quotas, Reception 4 Jan 1977, Recommendations (4 large files, alphabetical), Referrals (to other members), Regulatory Agencies, Requests - Agricultural Bulletins & Yearbooks, Requests - Calendars 1978, Requests - Calendars 1979, Requests - Campaign Materials, Requests - Flags 1977, Requests - Flags 1978, Requests - General Jan-Jun 1977, Requests - General Jul-Dec 1977.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-08, 1975 - 1978 (Box 126)
  Requests - General Jan-Jun 1978, Requests - General Jul-Dec 1978, Requests for Inauguration, Requests for Legislation Materials, Requests for McHugh Information, Requests for White House Tours, Resolutions, Résumés in District 77, 78, Résumés in District 75, 76, Résumés out of District 77, 78 (2 files), Right to Food Resolution, ROBEY, Bryant, Scientific Research Issues, Senior Citizens, Sikes Removal, SLADE, Catherine, Small Business Administration, Social Security Administration, Solicitations, Speeches (by MFM), Speeches (on floor), SPICER, John W., Staff Meetings.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-09, 1977 - 1978 (Box 67)
  Department of State, Co-Signed Statements (3 files), Arab Boycott, Sullivan County, taxes, Telegrams, Thank Yous from MFM (4 files), Thanks to MFM (2 files), 1978 Tours.
- Correspondence by Topic 095-10, 1977 - 1978 (Box 155)
  Tours, Town Meetings 1977 Jan-Mar, Town Meetings 1977 Apr-Nov, Town Meetings 1978 Jan-Jun, Trade, D of Transportation, D of Treasury, Ulster County, Unanswered Mail 1977, Unanswered Mail 1978, UPHOLF Norm, Veteran’s Administration, Visitors to DC (2 files), VOLK Franklin, Volunteers, WGHQ Requests, Walnut Mountain Healthcare Center, Wang (KERIVAN Donna), Weather Control, WEISER George, Welfare, WELV Requests, White House, WICHINSKY Louis, WILLIAMSON Elizabeth, WOLFSON Martin.
- District Issues, 1975 - 1982 (Box 175)
  Cornell University Miscellaneous (one file each 1975, 1976, 1977), 1" of “Energy” papers, no folder, Commerce Department, Exports, 1976-1977, Railroads: RRR Act, Conrail Takeover, Delaware - Andes (Village), Delaware - Colchester (Town), Delaware - Deposit (Village), Delaware - Hancock (Village), Delaware - Hancock, Delaware - Tompkins (Town), Delaware - Walton, Sullivan - Miscellaneous (one file each 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982), Sullivan - Association for Retarded Children, Sullivan - Community Action to Help the Economy, Sullivan - Catskill Resorts, Sullivan - Monticello - John Crawford Senior Housing, Sullivan - Community General Hospital, Sullivan - Sullivan County Community College, Sullivan - Sullivan County International Airport, Sullivan - Rural Housing Opportunities Company, Sullivan - United Cerebral Palsy - Hamilton House, Sullivan - Jobs Corps, Sullivan - County Park, Sullivan - Gypsy Moths, Sullivan - Federal Prison, Sullivan - SBA Designation, Sullivan - Mongaup Park, Sullivan - FWHA Rural Transpoortation, Sullivan - Bloomingburg, Sullivan - Callicoon, Sullivan - Denning, Sullivan - Eldred, Sullivan - Fallsburg, Sullivan - Fallsburg Sewer, Sullivan - Fallsburg - Mountain Pride, Sullivan - Ferndale Poultry Farm, Sullivan - Fremont, Sullivan - Grossinger’s.
- District Issues, 1978 - 1982 (Box 171)
  Tompkins County - Miscellaneous (one folder each 1978, 1979, 1980, 1981, 1982), Tompkins County - Airport, Tompkins County - Finger Lakes National Forest, Tompkins County - Flood 1981, Fort Drum, Eisenhower College, Tompkins County - Housing Miscellaneous, Tompkins County - Red Cross, Tompkins County - EDA Technical Assitance Program, Tompkins County - Ithaca Hydropower (2), Tompkins County - Groton SCM, Tompkins County - Ithaca Family Development Program, Tompkins County - Ithaca Gun, Tompkins County - Ithaca - NCR, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Challenge Industries, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Collegetown, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Fall Creek, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Center Ithaca, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Flooding Winter 1978, Tompkins County - Route 96, Tompkins County - Interlakes Finance (Bud Dillon), Tompkins County - Ithaca - Ithaca Center Project, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Iszards, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Ithaca Gun, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Ithaca Housing Authority, Tompkins County - Ithaca - HUD/CD, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Urban Development Action Grant, Tompkins County - Ithaca - WHCU, Tompkins County - Ithaca (Town), Tompkins County - Ithaca - Morse Chain, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Ithaca Neighborhood Housing Services, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Press Conference, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Miscellaneous 1981, Tompkins County - Ithaca (City) - Miscellaneous (one file each 1978, 1979, 1981, 1982), Tompkins County - Public Library, Tompkins County - National Guard Armory, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Reconstruction Home, Tompkins County - Regional Resource Letters, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Ithaca City School District, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Sewage Treatment, Tompkins County - Navel Sea Cadet Corps, Tompkins County - Six Mile Creek Erosion, Tompkins County - Six Mile Creek Hydropower, Tompkins County - Soil Conservation, Tompkins County - Ithaca - Strand Theatre.
- District Issues, 1978 - 1982 (Box 268)